Tom Leu

Software Developer

- ▼ tomleu@gmail.com
- in linkedin.com/in/spitzgoby
- github.com/spitzgoby

SKILLS

iOS, Objective-C, Swift, C, Xcode Advanced

Java, PHP, Python, OCaml, JavaScript SQL, HTML, CSS
Intermediate

Hadoop, Spark, Cassandra *Intermediate*

Microsoft Office, Photoshop Advanced

Mandarin Chinese (Written and Spoken)

Advanced

EDUCATION

December 2016 (Expected) Master of Liberal Arts, Software Engineering Cambridge, Massachusetts Harvard Extension School

Current GPA: 3.92

December 2010 Bachelor of Science, Mathematics Tuscaloosa, Alabama The University of Alabama

President's List, *Fall 2010*Dean's List, *Spring 2010*Accepted into Computer Based Honors Program, University Honors Program, and the Blount Undergraduate Initiative Honors Program

OPEN SOURCE PROJECTS

Written in Swift Tunits, Sole Contributor

CocoaPod library for common date and time calculations.

Written in Objective-C EvCal, Sole Contributor

iOS calendar application providing quick creation of recurring events.

Written in OCaml Matkit, Co-Contributor

Command line utilities for analyzing linear algebra equations using a custom grammar.

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Passionate and detail oriented developer who enjoys using new tools to solve interesting problems. Capable of working independently, but values teamwork and learning from others. Experienced in adapting to diverse cultures and environments. Able to communicate complex ideas.

EXPERIENCE

Aug 2012-Aug 2015 AP Calculus Teacher

Beijing, China Renmin University Affiliated High School

Developed and executed learning curriculum for collegiate level mathematics

Adapted communication style to local cultural norms increasing teaching effectiveness.

Helped students achieve significantly above average AP Test Scores.

Jul 2014-Dec 2014 iOS Developer (freelance) Beijing, China Gather Health

Worked collaboratively with designers to build iOS application. Researched usability concerns of target demographic and redesigned user interface to improve their experience by building responsive elements using Xcode and CocoaTouch. Refactored existing code base using MVC design patterns to increase development efficiency.

Used Xcode debugging tools to solve current and potential software bugs.

Mar 2011-Aug 2012 **Head Teacher** Beijing, China Children's Place

Managed small team providing English instruction to pre-kindergarten aged language learners. Developed lesson plans catering to the needs of young age language learners. Communicated with parents about their expectations and goals.

August 2006 - August 2010 Math Tutor

Tuscaloosa, Alabama The University of Alabama

Tutored over a thousand students in math classes including Algebra, Geometry and Calculus Improve students' use of educational technology Communicated analytical ideas ranging from simple to complex

June 2004 - August 2006 Summer Intern Birmingham, Alabama American Cast Iron Pipe Company

Worked on various production teams to ensure that orders were completed on time and met ACIPCO's high quality control standards

Integrated safety and efficiency practices to increase production and minimize accidents